(
"ai_sub_version": "2.8.2",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"ollama_search": (
"key": "**********"
),
"web_search_tool": "ollama",
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
The Great Ancient Detective's Bizarre Investigation
[Title: The Great Ancient Detective's Bizarre Investigation]
また悪い夢を見た。
Another bad dream.
陰惨な現場が日常の探偵という職業には、
悪夢は付き物と言ってもいいでしょう。
Perhaps nightmares are the penalty a detective pays
for being in a gruesome business.
だが、気にしている場合ではない。
So be it. It's not about to stop.
彼女のもとに、また新たな事件が
舞い込んできているからだ。
Not when there are new cases to be solved.
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? Children of man full of worries
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
UNLUCKY? Those who are not yet men
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
BE HAPPY! Aim without an ounce of slack,
UNDEAD 生きているんだし
UNDEAD You're alive, you know!
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
Even for the past you averted your gaze from
And your future with nothing fun to do
カウンセリング やれやれ
counseling, what a bummer
古今東西 ピースピース
Throughout all ages and places, peace peace!
UNDEAD
Lyrics, Music: Ayase
[Song: UNDEAD / Lyrics, Music: Ayase]
ねえ何だかどうして
Hey, why do I kinda get that feeling
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
that I'm fighting who-knows-what?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch, don't want to touch
過去の自分自分自分自分と
My past self self self self
もうとっくに死んでる
They've already died
透明な亡霊と対決
I'm confronting see-through ghosts
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
from deep in painful memories of my own tender youth
残念？ もう居ないのに
Too bad? Even though they're already gone
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? Prefer that? Ironic, right?
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is your current self see-through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, can't get rid of the label
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! Basically it's a complex,
取り憑かれているみたい
Like something’s got its hold on you
巻き付いたまま
I'm still all wrapped up
まだ離れない
they won't let me go—
在りし日の自分
in my past selves,
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
They're, not, dead!
The chain linking you and you together!
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to continue to change
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't go finding satisfaction
in resigning yourself to your discontentment
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
The fact that you refuse to even try to be happy, you coward!
この世この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, the present world we live in
is one devilishly odd fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Who knows what we'll come across next, a devil or a snake?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Our story finally starts to happen after chance
meetings and unfortunate encounters
さあ人か化物か 閑話休題 ピースピース
So, will it be a human or monster?
Now, back to the topic that's at hand, peace peace!
Past & Future
can't change the Past
run for the Future
カットイン
(Ka-ka!) Cu-cu-cut in!
何だかどうして
Why does it feel like
未来になんぞ
there's no hope
何の希望もない期待出来ない
to be had for the future
and nothing to expect
ような気がして
I kinda get that feeling
もう随分生きている
I've been living long enough.
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with deja-vu and the same stuff as always
素敵な出来事の気配もない
with no sign of anything wonderful coming up.
残念
Too bad…
積んだ経験の因果
Karma from accumulating experiences
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
with myths reduced to shells of formality and stale evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
The point, all I want is stimulation
同じ味がする
Everything tastes the same
アンデッド！
Undead!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖
Not dead, you and your chain
何時の世も 過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future are in the present
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of living honestly
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
アンデッド！
Undead!
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
Not dead, I'm telling you
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness
人で在れ
Be human
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is as good as dead, a corpse-like undead
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? Children troubled
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Those who don't become people
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Aim without slack
アンデッド! 生きているんだろ
Undead! You're alive, right?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Whether you wallow in unhappiness or become happy
そう全部全部お前だ
Yes, it's all, all you
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Throughout the ages, everything, all creation, peace peace
Past and future / Can't change the past
Past and future / Run for the future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Wherever there are people, there is always sorrow
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters
IRIS OUT
[Title: IRIS OUT]
駄目駄目駄目 脳みその中から「やめろ馬鹿」と喚くモラリティ
Damn, damn, damn, a morality
that shouts "Quit it, idiot" from inside the brain
ダーリンベイビーダーリン
Darling baby darling
半端なくラブ！ときらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィ
I'm terribly in love! Philosophy
that makes me twinkle and float
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
It's dying-ly cute, the way you look up
なにがし法に触れるくらい
To the point of breaking some law
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering insanity, before I know it, I'm squandering
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You, who were born into this world, are at fault
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
This lovesickness is so terribly hard
バラバラんなる頭とこの身体
My head and this body falling apart
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て アイリスアウト
"I love you" sprays out from my carotid artery
Iris out
一体どうしようこの想いを どうしよう
What should I do with this feeling? What should I do?
あばらの奥をザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The coarse sugar deep in my ribs
will melt and become vomit
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
My pupils are blown wide open,
I feel like I'm drowning
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, you are the only correct answer in this world
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
I can't win even if I flip over
君だけルールは適用外
You are the only exception to the rules
四つともオセロは黒しかない
Even in Othello, all four corners are only black
カツアゲ放題
All-you-can-steal
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
Abada Kedavra you shot with a smile
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
Stigma on your forehead, sorry about that
矢を刺して 貫いて ここ弱点
I'll pierce it, run it through, this is the weak point
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
It's dying-ly cute, the way you look up
なにがし法に触れるくらい
To the point of breaking some law
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering insanity, before I know it, I'm squandering
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You, who were born into this world, are at fault
パチモンでもいい何でもいい
A knock-off is fine, anything is fine
今君と名付いてる全て欲しい
I want everything that is named "you" right now
頸動脈からアイラブユーが噴き出て アイリスアウト
"I love you" sprays out from my carotid artery
Iris out
一体どうしようこの想いを どうしよう
What should I do with this feeling? What should I do?
あばらの奥をザラメが溶けてゲロになりそう
The coarse sugar deep in my ribs
will melt and become vomit
瞳孔バチ開いて溺れ死にそう
My pupils are blown wide open,
I feel like I'm drowning
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, you are the only correct answer in this world
ある殺人事件を調べてほしいという匿名の依頼。
Like this one. An anonymous plea for help
in the investigation of a murder.
手紙に被害者の情報はほとんどなく、ましてや犯人の情報は皆無であった。
The letter had little on the victim
and nothing on the killer.
あまりに不可解な謎の手紙。
A letter too mysterious and cryptic,
イタズラの可能性もある、けど...
it could even be a prank. But...
おや？
Huh?
おはよう、アーニャ！依頼された絵が完成しましたよ〜。
Good morning, Anya! I finished your commission~~
一伊那爾栖（ニノマエ・イナニス）。
Ninomae Ina'nis.
この町一番の肖像画家だ。
The greatest portrait artist on this side of the tracks.
あの...私の顔に何かついてます？
Um... is there something on my face?
事件の手がかりがない以上、解決の糸口を見つけるには彼女の才能を頼る必要があった。
With no leads, the detective needed a talent like
that to jumpstart her investigation.
アーニャ？
Anya?
とは言えこういった事件では、誰もが容疑者になりうる。
Then again, in a case like this,
anyone could be the killer.
そう、この純粋で可憐なイナでさえーー
What if sweet, innocent Ina-
わああーっ！
WAH!
うわっ！
Ah!
ごめんなさい。じーっと見られてたからつい。どうかしましたか？
Sorry, but you were just staring at me.
Is everything okay?
いや別に...それっぽい雰囲気を出そうとしてただけだ。
Yeah, I'm just building atmosphere.
それより、頼んでた絵はできた？
Uh, anyway, you did the picture I asked for?
できました〜！
I did it!
イェイ！
Yeah!
描きましたけど、それ誰なんですか？
Who's this a picture of anyway?
この絵は誰ですか？
いま調べている事件の被害者だよ。
The victim from a case I'm working.
あっ、報酬はいつもの値段でいいよね？
Anyway, you're charging the standard fee, right?
悪いけど今回はツケにしといて。
Sorry, but can you put it on my tab?
でも前回もツケって言ってましたよね…。
But you put the last one on your tab too...
じゃあイナは特別に…1回だけタダで依頼を受けてあげるから。
Maybe we could do a trade then? I'll solve one case for you for free.
それよりも…歌がいいな～。
Ooorrr... I'll trade you for a song~
はい？
Huh?
だって！アーニャさん最近ずっと怖い顔してますよ。
Come on! You've been so serious lately.
たまには息抜きしないと。
You gotta get loose sometimes.
私と1曲歌ってくれたら、絵は差し上げます。どうですか？
So one song with me, and you get to keep the picture. That's the deal~
そこまで言うなら…歌ってやるか！
If that's what you want, then alright!
大きな白いキャンバスに虚構のコラージュを貼るよ
I'll put a fictional collage on a big white canvas.
どこからでもキレイに映る 誇張された天使が居たよ
There was an exaggerated angel who looked pretty no matter how you looked at it.
きゅびずむ
[Title: Kyuubizumu (Cubism)]
まだ少し歪んだ新しくなくても見えた
I could see it, even if it wasn't new, still a bit distorted.
生きるため立ち寄った美術館のセザンヌに
In Cezanne's paintings at the art museum I stopped by to live.
何もわからない名前だ知らずに見ても欠けた
I don't understand anything, even looking at the unknown name, it's missing.
赤をずっと塗り込んだ馬鹿げた素振りだった
It was a foolish gesture, keeping on painting with red.
不自由で下手な絵画 だけどそこがいいな
A restricted and poorly made painting, but that's what's good about it.
下らない線だな そのまま
What a worthless line, just like that.
切って貼った顔
Cut and pasted face.
咲いて見えた痣 痣
Bruises that looked like they were blooming.
ララララララ 嗤うように浮いた 浮いた 甘ら
La la la la la la, it floated as if laughing, floated, sweet.
ギュッと裂いてから
After tearing it tightly.
ギュッと泣いたから
Because I cried tightly.
吐いて泣いたから から
Because I vomited and cried.
ララララララ 嘆く壁に描いたパブロ・ピカソ
La la la la la la, Pablo Picasso painted on the grieving wall.
なぜか私のことだなって眺めちゃったよ
For some reason, I gazed at it, thinking it was about me.
これが欲しいなって感じたら セザンヌの絵を希望なんてね
If I feel like I want this, I'll wish for a Cezanne painting, just kidding.
同情が撮られてじっと見てたよ
Sympathy was captured and I was staring at it.
偽物、嘘を重ねれば 本物の意味あるのかな
If fakes and lies are layered, is there any meaning to the real thing?
真実、痛いと書いたまま 飾り落ちて床で死んでた
The truth, while written as painful, fell off its decoration and died on the floor.
青をずっと塗り込んだ やっぱりよかった
I kept on painting with blue, it was good after all.
卑しい線だな 今もまあ
What a vulgar line, even now.
切って貼った顔
Cut and pasted face.
咲いて散った花 花
Flowers that bloomed and scattered.
ララララララ 嗤うように見えた 見えた 体の
La la la la la la, it looked like it was laughing, looked, of the body.
ギュッと裂いてから
After tearing it tightly.
ギュッと泣いたから
Because I cried tightly.
吐いて泣いたから から
Because I vomited and cried.
ララララララ 嘆く壁に描いたパブロ・ピカソ
La la la la la la, Pablo Picasso painted on the grieving wall.
私、嘘のピカソ
I am the fake Picasso.
やっと来た。
Finally.
こんな不気味な場所で待たせないでほしいんだけど。
This is a creepy place to make someone wait.
現場を調べたらKFPの近くに寄るから、店の近くで待っててって言ったのに。
I told you I'd come to the nearby KFP after investigating the crime scene.
そんなの無理！
Not a chance!
アンタと話すだけでもイヤなのに、話してるところを人に見られたりしたらそれこそ最悪。
It's bad enough I have to talk to you. I don't want others to be around to see it.
そんなアンタが手を貸してくれるなんて意外だけどね。
I'm surprised you're willing to cooperate in the first place.
それは…例の殺人事件以降、いろいろ妙なことが起こってるの。
Yeah, well, ever since the murder, weird things have been happening.
アンタが解決してくれるなら、こうやって会うのもやむなしよ。イヤだけど。
I figure if you can help solve it, then it's worth the trouble of meeting with you.
ほんの少しね。
Just barely.
妙なことが起こってる？
What weirdness?
「人の形をした黒い影が見えた」って報告が、うちの従業員からちょくちょく出てるの。
Some of my employees have been complaining about seeing a shadowy figure.
話によれば、最初は夢の中にそれが現れたんだけど、今は起きてる時も見えるって――
They say it started with bad dreams, but now some are seeing it even when they're—
アーニャ！
Anya!
だ…大丈夫。それより…
I'm... fine, don't worry about me.
これ見て。
Look at this.
まったくもう、アンタはいつも大げさすぎ…ん？
Hmph. Course. You're just always being overly dramatic... huh?
おかしいな。現場の証拠品は警察が全部回収したはずなのに。
Weird. I figured the cops would have already collected all the evidence.
この近くに住んでるKFPの従業員で、被害者のことを知ってる者は？
Did any of your employees who live nearby know the victim?
いない。
Nope.
分かった。新しい情報が入ったらまた教えて。
Alright. Let me know if you hear anything else.
ちょっと待った！
Wait!
それだけ？私の時間を奪っておいてタダで帰るつもり？
That's it? You're not even gonna compensate me for my time?
従業員のためかと思いきや、結局カネかい。
I thought you were doing this to help your employees.
タダ働きはしない主義なの。
I'm still a businesswoman.
いま持ち合わせがないんだけど、代わりに歌で支払うっていうのはどう？
Well, I don't have any cash on me, but I can pay you in song.
ウソでしょ？歌うの？アンタと？
Seriously? You think I'd want to sing? With you?
イナは歌で喜んでくれたけどなー。
Ina accepted payment in song.
ただ、イナと歌うのは楽しいけど、
But then, singing with her is fun.
But then, singing with her is fun,
キアラと歌ってもなあ...
but with you...
それどういう意味？
With me, what?
私の歌じゃダメってこと？
You don't think I'm good enough for you?!
やってやろうじゃないの！ほら、さっさと歌うよ！
Let's go, punk! You and me, right now!
全部 全部 アンタのせいだ
It's all, all your fault
反吐が出るくらいにウザったいわ
It's so annoying I could vomit
何かに縋って諂って
Clinging to something, flattering
期待したアタシが馬鹿だった
I was a fool for having expectations
ご機嫌伺いの八方美人
A people-pleaser currying favor
それ故にアンチな一生Gimme
So gimme a lifetime of being an anti
浅いキャパシティ まいどおおきに
Shallow capacity, thanks as always
つまるとこ 人生ずっと地味
In the end, life is just plain
｢憎たらしい! ｣｢痛々しい! ｣
“How hateful!” “How pitiful!”
無視出来ないのが一層
It’s even more...
腹立たしい 苛立たしい
...enraging and irritating that I can't ignore it
そろそろ飽きた 自画自賛に
I'm getting tired of your self-praise
(Look around!!)
ライクの反対はアパシー
The opposite of like is apathy
≒ 繋がれた証
≒ Proof of being connected
切り離せない関係
A relationship that can't be severed
逸らしてしまいたいわ
I just want to turn away
これは所謂 ヘイトスピーチ
This is what they call hate speech
匿名性の声明を
Putting a declaration of anonymity...
生命に載せてんだ
...on my very life
鳴り止まないサイレン
The siren that won't stop ringing
近づく度に痙攣
Spasms every time it gets closer
赤信号にずっと従順です。
Always obedient to the red light.
大体 アナタのコト アタシ
Generally, when it comes to you,
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I HATE HATE HATE HATE HATE you
Omg 情けない 最早
Omg, how miserable, at this point
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say BYE-BYE-BYE-BYE-BYE
脳内も予測不能 故に
Even my brain is unpredictable, hence
解解解解解は無い
There is NO NO NO NO NO solution
どうだい? アタシのコト アナタ
How about it? Do you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった?
...HATE HATE HATE HATE HATE me now?
あァ 百害あって一利ナシ
Ah, all harm and no benefit
nothing not see
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if I stack up 'what-ifs,' it's just nicotine
I miss youって近付いた結末は
The end of getting close saying 'I miss you' is...
凡ミス 凡ミス
...a careless mistake, a careless mistake
センキュー 反面教師
Thank you, bad example
後味 一生消えてくんないわ
The aftertaste will never disappear
よしよし いい子ね
There, there, good child
笑顔振り撒き パラパラ いい子ね
Scattering smiles, a good child
だけど だけど その本性は?
But, but, what's your true nature?
善悪の区別も付かないの? 笑 はぁ。
Can't you tell good from evil? Lol. Sigh.
減点方式で取り巻く環境に巻かれて
Swept up in an environment of demerit points
生涯、痛い! 痛い! 痛い! も聞かれないわ! って
I won't even hear 'it hurts! it hurts! it hurts!' in my life
当然の報いにクラっちゃった
I got hit by the natural consequences
人は鏡なんです
People are mirrors
実のところ 依存は両辺です
Actually, dependence is on both sides
シャットダウンしても付き纏う
It haunts me even if I shut down
己の弱さが不甲斐ない
My own weakness is pathetic
全部 全部 アンタのせいって
Saying it's all, all your fault
反吐が出るくらいに止まんないわ
It won't stop, to the point of vomiting
いっその事 切り離せた方が楽なのにな
It would be easier if I could just cut it off
大体 アナタのコト アタシ
Generally, when it comes to you,
ダイダイダイダイダイキライ
I HATE HATE HATE HATE HATE you
Omg 情けない 最早
Omg, how miserable, at this point
バイバイバイバイバイしたい
I want to say BYE-BYE-BYE-BYE-BYE
脳内も予測不能 故に
Even my brain is unpredictable, hence
解解解解解は無い
There is NO NO NO NO NO solution
どうだい? アタシのコト アナタ
How about it? Do you...
ダイダイダイダイダイキライになった?
...HATE HATE HATE HATE HATE me now?
あァ 百害あって一利ナシ
Ah, all harm and no benefit
nothing not see
もしタラレバ並べてもニコチンだし
Even if I stack up 'what-ifs,' it's just nicotine
I miss youって近付いた結末は
The end of getting close saying 'I miss you' is...
凡ミス 凡ミス
...a careless mistake, a careless mistake
センキュー 反面教師
Thank you, bad example
後味 一生消えてくんないわ
The aftertaste will never disappear
はァ、もう、誰なの？
Sigh, who is it now?
はい...
Come in.
アーニャ、ヤッホー！
Hey Anya, ya doing okay?
って、大丈夫そう？
Wait, are you okay?
なんか顔色悪いね。
You look kind of... not great.
大丈夫...じゃないかもね。
Thanks... maybe not.
ちょっと横になったほうがいいんじゃない？
You just need sleep!
周りをぐるぐる走ってあげるから、
Lie down, and I'll run in circles...
わための数を数えるといいよ！
...so you can count me~
心配かけてごめん、でも今は寝たらダメんだ。
Sorry, but not now.
なぜなら、あともうちょっとでこの事件を解決できそうなんだから！
I'm close to cracking this case wide open!
そお？
You sure?
そうかも、そうじゃないかも。
I don't know! Yes? Maybe?
わかんないけど、とりあえずヒントは揃ったんだ。
I do have all the hints...
ほな、難しいか。
That doesn't seem very sure...
わため先輩、ほどほどにしておきましょう。
Watame-senpai, I think you're annoying her.
わためは悪くないよねぇ？
Watame did nothing wrong.
これが事件を解く鍵なんだ。
This is an important clue!
探偵の直感がそう言ってる。
I can feel it in my gut,
でもDNA鑑定では何もわからなかった。
...but a DNA trace was a dead end.
じゃあ、これは何なんだ？これは何なんだ？！
So what does it mean? What does it mean?!
その布でそんなにお困りなら...
If you're so troubled by that cloth...
あ、じゃあ、わためが食べてあげる！
Oh! I could eat it.
ねぇアーニャ、それちょっと見せてくれる？
Hey Anya? Can I take a look at that?
この布についてわかったことはあるけど...
If I tell you something about this cloth,
それを教えたら、ちょっと休憩しない？
will you agree to take a break?
一旦仕事の手は止めて、私達と遊ぼうよ。
Maybe do something fun with us before you go back to work?
じゃあ、一緒に歌でも歌う？
We could sing together.
この街では、情報は歌で買うものみたいだし。
That seems to be the going rate for information around here.
お、楽しそう！
Oh, that sounds fun!
オッケー。
Alright...
その布には、魔力の痕跡を感じるんだ。
...I can sense a magical residue on this cloth.
そんなバカな
That can't be true.
ねえ、アイリスはネフィリム、忘れたの？
Hey, I'm a Nephilim, remember?
魔力を感じとるなんてお手のもの
We get a bonus to detect magic!
あれ？アーニャもこの布が怪しいと思ってたんじゃないの？
Wait... you already had your suspicions about the cloth, didn't you?
そうだけどさ。
Yeaaaah...
でも殺人事件と超常現象なんて混ぜたらダメな奴でしょ。
but supernatural stuff happening in a murder case? They're not supposed to mix.
そう？でもそういうアニメとかドラマも...
Really? But in some shows...
まあまあ、物騒な話はそのくらいにして、
Enough murder talk.
みんなで歌っちゃおう！
Let's sing~!
ULTRA C / Lyrics: Reel / Music: TeddyLoid, Giga
[Visual Text: ULTRA C / Lyrics: Reel / Music: TeddyLoid, Giga]
この路地を抜けろ Awake now
Break through this alley, Awake now
(僕ら覚醒 アップデート ey)
(We’re awakening, updating, ey)
ギラギラ光らせた いいないいなそのカラット
Gleaming and shining, wow, those carats are so nice
目立っちゃうな自然に視線を独り占め
You naturally stand out, monopolizing all the attention
この手口は盗めない
This tactic can’t be stolen
答えなら「好きなだけ」が極まってく
The answer “As much as you like” is reaching its peak
一秒前完全アップデート ya ya
Fully updated a second ago, ya ya
不安ぐっばい 自分以外は敵じゃない
Goodbye to anxiety, everyone else isn’t the enemy
お利口御無用 指を立てろ
No need to be polite, stick up your fingers
Ha~ 揺れろ運命
Ha~ Shake it, fate
Ah~ あたしらしいウルトラC
Ah~ My own ultra C
その感情を燃料に持ち込む延長戦へ全能
Using those emotions as fuel, let’s carry on into overtime, omnipotent
嗚呼、体が
Ah, my body
この生き様で Make some noise
Living this way, make some noise
見舞う We gotta go メディカルボイス
We’ll strike with a medical voice
宿した熱狂は伝播する 真っ向から着弾
The frenzy we carry spreads out, hitting its mark head-on
もらうわ大歓声 (Burn out na na uh!)
I’ll take that big applause (Burn out na na uh!)
What I want to touch down
What I want is to touch down
(燃やせ革命 アップアップデート hey)
(Burn the revolution, update hey)
Go all out
(僕が覚醒、逆転 ey)
(I’m awakening, overturning, ey)
ひとりきりじゃ Just kidding 君とだから Dreaming
Alone, it’s just kidding, but with you, it’s dreaming
間違いだらけ 勘違いもして ときめきをリテイク
Full of mistakes, misunderstandings, retake the excitement
ey 失っても尚コンティニュー 支払った代償の自分
Ey, even if I lose, I’ll continue, the price I paid for myself
あの日に…uh してないわけない後悔
That day… uh, there’s no way I don’t regret it
胸に飾れ 前向き直せ 唱えて 信じてくれ
Adorn it on your chest, straighten up, chant it... Believe in me
(諦め悪いって？)
(You think I’m bad at giving up?)
青く燃ゆる僕は炎 時は経てど恋うは心
I’m a blue-burning flame, though time passes, the heart still yearns
誰だ誰だ誰だあたしだ さあお任せ
Who is it, who is it, who is it? It’s me, now leave it to me
(Burn out na na uh!) Ha~
抜ける茨 BAE! Make some noise
Breaking through the thorns, BAE! Make some noise
有終の美 Get up! Hey, Raise the bro
The beautiful finale, Get up! Hey, raise the bro
臆した逆境に下剋上 とうとう役満
Rising up against the timid adversity, finally reaching the jackpot
あげるわ大団円！ (Burn out na na uh!)
I’ll give you a happy ending! (Burn out na na uh!)
What I want to touch down
What I want is to touch down
(燃やせ革命 アップデート hey)
(Burn the revolution, update hey)
Go all out
(僕が覚醒、逆転 ey)
(I’m awakening, overturning, ey)
以上がこちらで調べた情報です。いかがですか？
So that's everything I've got so far. What do you think?
そして彼女は大空警察を訪れる。
And so, she visits the Oozora Police.
数々の難事件を解決してきた優秀な警察から、今回の事件に関する更なる情報を得るべく...
With their stellar track of solving mysterious cases like this one easily, she hopes that they can give her some leads.
探偵は警察署を訪れていた。
The detective was visiting the police station.
だからー、事件の捜査は我々プロに任せとけばいいんだよ。
I think you should leave the investigating to the professionals.
何？被害者の服に魔力の痕跡があったって？
I mean, magical residue on the victim's clothing?
そうだ、そんなバカな話があるか！
Yes! That is very silly!
こいつ次、自分自身が凶器かもしれないとか言い出すんじゃないですか、署長。
Next, she's going to tell me that SHE'S actually involved and might be the murder weapon, Chief.
それだ！
Wait, that's it!
はぁ？
Huh?
こいつ今、自分が凶器だって自白した？
Did she just confess to being the murder weapon?
よく分かんないっす。ボクが言ったのはただの冗談で...
I'm not sure. I was just joking about that...
もしかしてボク、無意識のうちに真実をつかんでいたのか！？
What if I subconsciously knew the truth this whole time!?
お前天才か！？
You are a genius!?
おや、これはいよいよ事件解決... になってしまうのか？
Oh my, could this possibly mean the case is solved?
事件解決しちゃった！
I solved the case!
違う違う、私は凶器じゃないですよ。
No, no, no. I'm not the murder weapon.
異議あり！さっき自白しただろ！
OBJECTION! You already confessed!
私が言いたいのは、この事件にはまた別の古代兵器が関わっているかもしれないということ。
What I mean is, maybe there was another ancient weapon involved.
だから布に魔力が残っていたんだ。
That would explain the magical residue on the cloth.
なんだそういうことか...
I guess that makes sense.
僕が事件を解決できたと思ったのに...
But I wanted to solve the case...
まあ次がんばれよ。
You will solve the next one.
でもなあ、現場の近くで変なものを見たっていう報告も届いているんだ。
But we've also gotten reports of people seeing strange things near the murder scene.
その魔力の痕跡とやらが超常的な力によるものだっていうなら... 変な幻覚が見えた人がいるのもそいつの影響ってこと？
If the involvement of something supernatural explains the magical residue, does it also cover those weird visions?
それはまだ分かりませんが、謎は必ず解いてみせましょう。
I'm not sure yet, but I'm going to find out.
じゃあうちの捜査資料を持って行っていいよ。
Then we will give you our case file to help out.
民間人にあげちゃダメっすよ！
You can't give that to a civilian!
でもこいつさぁ、なんか天才の匂いしね？
But she seems like a genius.
さっきはボクのこと天才って言ったじゃないですかぁ...。
But that was my thing...
どんな情報でも助かりますよ。
Any information you have would be useful.
ただし！資料が欲しいなら、タダというわけにはいかんな！
Fiiiine! But if you want our files, then we need something in return.
これ、また歌う流れですか？
Could that thing be, perhaps, a song?
㋰責任集合体
Lyrics, Music: マサラダ
[Song: Responsibility Collection]
[Lyrics, Music: Masalada]
おれは しらない なにも しらない
I don't know, I know nothing.
なにも みてない だれも みてない
I didn't see anything, nobody did.
そらを みても みえない よるの
You can't see the sky at night.
かけた つきに うさぎ
There's a rabbit in the waning moon.
これは なんだ それが なにか？
What is this? What is that?
ここは たのし それで よろし
I'm happy here, that's all.
はしる にげる にがす そらす
Running, escaping, letting go, averting eyes.
月の 欠けた 場所へ
Toward the place where the moon is missing.
あらら あらら あらら あらら
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
妄想 止め処なく
Endless delusions.
創造 咎めなく
Creation without reproach.
衝動 収まらず
The impulse can't be quelled.
なぜか なぜか なぜか なぜかしら？
Why, why, why, I wonder why?
最悪だ！ 公序良俗を剥いで脱いで踊れ！
It's the worst! Strip off public order and morals and dance!
いや最低か！ なんでなんでつって なんかなんか高鳴って
No, it's the lowest! Asking why, why, my heart's pounding for some reason.
最悪だ！ どうもこうもしねぇよ勝手にしやがれ！
It's the worst! I can't do anything about it, so just suit yourself!
いや最低か！ いやーもうほんと 最悪だ！
No, it's the lowest! No, really, it's the worst!
だ！だ！だ！だ！ お、おう…
...orst! orst! orst! orst! Oh, uh...
ねてもさめてもつきまとう
Haunting me whether I'm awake or asleep.
みえぬいしきのうらがわに
On the back side of unseen consciousness...
おおきくあいたくろいあな
...is a large, gaping black hole.
わかる わかる わかる
I understand, I understand, I understand.
許す 許せん 許す 許せ
Forgive, unforgivable, forgive, forgive.
かわいい えへへ むふふ こわい
Cute, ehehe, mufufu, scary.
りんご ごりら らくご ごじら
Apple, Gorilla, Rakugo, Godzilla.
らくだ だぼら らまだん
Camel, Boaster, Ramadan.
わたしたち、ぜったいにみてません！！ いってません！！
We absolutely didn't see it!! We didn't say it!!
きいてません！！しったこっちゃありません！！
We didn't hear it!! It's none of our business!!
ひかりをいっし！！かげにひとつき！！
Losing the light!! Stabbing the shadow!!
ゆるされざるしこうを！！あてはまらないいじょうを！！
Unforgivable thoughts!! Anomalies that don't fit!!
つつんでいきていこうじゃありませんか！！
Why don't we live by wrapping them all up!?
行動 名も持たず
Actions without a name.
狂騒 意味もなく
Frenzy without meaning.
永劫 自己満足
Eternal self-satisfaction.
だから だから だから だからかな？
So, so, so, I wonder if that's why?
最高だ！ 脳が硬化してんだ ぶっ壊して叫べ！
It's the best! Your brain is hardening, so break it and scream!
いや最高か！？ なんでなんでつって 跋扈跋扈跳ねちゃって
No, is it the best!? Asking why, why, rampant and jumping around.
最高だ！ 愚行奇行で結構 勝手に生きたれ！
It's the best! Folly and eccentricity are fine, just live as you please!
いや最高か！ いやーもうほんと 最高だ！
No, is it the best!? No, really, it's the best!
だ！だ！だ！だ！ イエッサー！!
...est! est! est! est! Yes sir!!
むかしむかしのおもいつき
A long, long time ago whim.
むいぎむいみのひとだかり
A meaningless and pointless crowd.
むじゃきむてきのうまれつき
Innocent and invincible from birth.
それが それが それが
That is, that is, that is...
㋰責任集合体 アンタもワタシも関係ない
Responsibility Collection. It has nothing to do with you or me.
㋰責任集合体 楽しくやってりゃ無問題
Responsibility Collection. If you're having fun, there's no problem.
勝手にやってりゃ問題ナシ
No problem if you're doing it on your own.
俺は 知らない 何も 知らない
I don't know, I know nothing.
何も 見てない 誰も 見てない
I didn't see anything, nobody did.
責任集合体
[Title: Responsibility Collective]
超常的な力が殺人事件に関わっている？
A supernatural occurrence, happening in a murder case?
いやいやそんな、ねえ？
That's just unbelievable.
にわかには信じがたいが、今の手がかりから推理するとそういうことになる。
She had a hard time believing it, but all the hints said otherwise.
まだパズルのピースがピタリとはまらないこの不思議で奇妙な事件。
Still, there were pieces of this puzzle that refused to fit, this strange and bizarre incident.
探偵は信頼できる情報源に頼ることにした。
so the detective turned to a reliable source for help.
あっ、来てくれたー
Hey, I'm glad—
…なんで君達まで？
…And why are you guys also here?
ゼータが来るって聞いたから、アーニャにちょっかいかけてやろうと思って！
We heard Zeta was coming over, and decided to bug ya!
はいはい。
Yes, yes, I see.
もー！つれないなぁ。
Aww, come on!
それはそうと…ゼータ、何か掴めた？
Anyway, Zeta, did you find anything?
もちろん！優秀なシークレットエージェントなので！
Of course! I'm not an elite secret agent for nothing.
イナの描いた似顔絵と大空警察の資料から、被害者の身元を特定できたよ。
Between the portrait from Ina and the files from the Oozora Police, I've been able to positively ID the murder victim.
でも…ちょっと変なんだよね。
But… what I found is weird.
変？
How so?
被害者の履歴を調べたところ、その人物は何百年も前の時代の人だったんだ。
Well, when I investigated their history, I found that they actually lived centuries ago.
でもその人物が、数日前に死体で発見された…話がつながらないよ。
So how they were also somehow murdered just days ago… it doesn't make any sense.
アーニャからもらった情報に間違いがあったとか？
Did you perhaps confuse your information? Or…
なるほど。やっとつながってきた。
Actually, things are finally starting to make sense.
えっ？
Oh?
一人の被害者が、過去と現在で二度死んだことになる。
A victim caught between two times.
誰かが時間と次元をねじ曲げて、そんな状況を作り出した。
One who died in two different ways.
なかなかできることじゃない。でも君なら可能でしょ。
Not many exist who can cause time and dimensions to warp in a way to make that possible… but you're one of them.
さすがは名探偵。
Well done, detective.
ちょっと時間がかかりすぎかな。
Took you long enough.
危うくネタばらしするとこだった。
I was this close to telling ya the whole thing.
レイネが書いてくれた、この匿名の手紙もいいヒントになったよ。
You helped enough with this "anonymous" letter about the murder.
えっ、バレてた？
O-oh, you figured out that was me?
書き方のクセで分かる。
I recognized your writing style.
待って、どういうこと？ムーナと被害者にどんな関係があるの？
W-wait, I don't get it. What does Moona have to do with the victim?
ムーナは、別の時空で殺された遺体を我々がいるこの時空へ移動させたんだ。
She took a murder victim from another space and time, and moved them into our dimension.
ゼータが特定した人物は、この世界線における同一人物ってこと。
The one you IDed was this universe's version of the same person.
なるほど…？でもどうしてそんなことを？
Uh… okay. But then why?
理由も気になるけど、それより確かめたいことがある。
That is an important question, but there's one I want answered even more.
ムーナが…私にあの日夢を見せたの？
Are you… responsible for my dreams?
それは違う。
No.
あなたがあの夢を見ていることを知って、私はあの夢が生まれる根源を調べてみた。
After I learned about your dreams, I used my powers to search for the source of them.
そして見つけたのが、次元の向こう側から声を届けようとする魂。
I found a spirit reaching out from time and dimensions.
私はその魂のために橋渡しをしてあげただけ…。
All I've done is try to help them by making the bridge a little easier….
私も手伝ったよ！というか、私のアイデア。
With my help! I mean, it was my idea….
そう。
True.
ただやり方が悪かったのか、アーニャの見たものが他の人にも見えちゃったみたい。
Though doing it this way has caused some of what you've been experiencing to leak to other people.
巻き込んだKFPの従業員には後でお詫びしなきゃ…。
We're going to have to apologize to the KFP workers….
でもその魂が、どうして私に声を届けようとしてるの？
But why is the spirit reaching out to me of all people?
それは私に訊くことじゃないわね。私が話すべきことじゃない。
It wouldn't be right for me to answer those questions. It's not my story to tell.
あの魂に心を開いてあげて。それだけでいい。
Open yourself up to the spirits, and they'll do the rest.
心をもっと開く方法なら知ってるよ！
I got a way to make yourself more open to spirits!
それって歌？
Is it through song?
えっ？なんで分かったの？
Huh? How'd you know?
まあ、勘かな…
Lucky guess…
ワン、ツー！
One, two!
Sympathy
[Song: Sympathy]
Lyrics, Music: Eve
思い返していた
I think back,
思い出の中で泣いていた
and in my memories, I was crying.
不確かな夢と孤独を
Carrying uncertain dreams and loneliness,
抱えて笑ってた
I was smiling.
この痛みも傷も
That pain and those wounds,
いたいけな瞳も
and those innocent eyes tooー
無に帰してしまいそうな
All seem like they'll all be for naught.
焦りと不安が滲んで
Impatience and uneasiness blur together,
涙に飲まれてしまう
and I'm going to be swallowed up by my tears.
誰一人欠けることはない
But there is a never a time when even a single one of us is missing,
ちぐはぐだった 僕らの想いが
and though we were separate, our feelings
音になって繋ぐ
become music and connect.
こだましていく
Echoing throughout,
忘れないよう かき鳴らした日々を
so we wouldn't forget the days that we strummed out.
あの日僕らは
And we know that the "us" of back then
間違っていなかったんだと知る
weren’t mistaken.
閉ざしてしまいこんだ
Looking for a flash of light
一閃の光 探して
that has been shut away.
君の声を聴かせて
Let me hear your voice;
ここにいるって 叫んでくれよ
shout out for me that "I'm right here!"
その手を離さないで
And don't let go of my hand.
世界に僕だけが
It’s as if I'm the only one
取り残されて
Left behind in this world,
...楽に生きられたかな
...maybe it would be easier to just live on by myself.
憧れ 理想に強く惹かれる感情が
The thrill of being captivated by our dreams and ideals
僕らを引き寄せてしまうのなら
Is pulling ourselves closer towards it,
応えて
So we'll answer its call.
こだましていく
Our music echoes throughout;
まだ終わっちゃいないんだ僕ら
We're not done quite yet!
延長戦だろう この音が途切れるまで
We're going into overtime, and it won't end until this music cuts out.
こだましていく
It's echoing...
まだ終わっちゃいないんだ僕ら
We're not done quite yet!
延長戦だろう この音が途切れるまで
We're going into overtime, and it won't end until this music cuts out.
子供の頃に描いたヒーロー
Oh hero, the one we fantasized about when we were children,
君の出番が待ってる
Your entrance is awaiting you!
こだましていく
Our music echoes throughout;
忘れないようにかき鳴らした日々を
The days that we strummed out so we wouldn't forget about them echoed throughout,
あの日僕らは 間違っていなかったんだと知る
And we know that the "us" of back then weren’t mistaken.
閉ざしてしまいこんだ 一閃の光探して
We're looking for a flash of light that has been shut away.
君の声を聴かせて ここにいるって
Let me hear your voice; shout out for me that "I'm right here!"
叫んでくれよ その手を離さないで
And don't let go of my hand.
魂に心を開け？ 簡単に言ってくれる。
Opening up to the spirit? That was a tall order.
探偵になる前の彼女'の人生において、他者に心を開くのは危険な行為だった。
In her life before being a detective, opening up to someone was dangerous.
今でもその本能は変わらない。
That instinct still lingers.
結局何も進展はなかった。
This was getting her nowhere.
謎はまだ残っているが、彼女はここのところ無理が続いていた。
She still had questions she needed answered, but maybe she had wound herself up too much.
少し休まなければ。
She needed a break.
Hello everyone!
I'm Hatsune Miku, a virtual Idol!
Well, that's what everyone seems to think, but secretly I'm...
(Uryaoi!! Uryaoi!! Oh, fighter!)
M@GICAL☆CURE! LOVE SHOT!
[Title: M@GICAL☆CURE! LOVE SHOT!]
(Super powerful Miku-chan!)
(Uryaoi!! Uryaoi!! Oh, cyber!)
(Miku Miku Miku go!)
一緒に歌おう！
Let's sing together!
I wake up to a call
Put my frilly outfit on now
It's time I open up my eyes and start the day
I combat till the dawn
Until every villain’s gone wah!
A clumsy trip and now I’ve fallen to my butt
With my magical phone
And a silly little ringtone
I’ll shout a magic word and set the world in place
Whatever it may cost
There’s no reason to stop
For a world that I cherish and love
(TSKR!)
Monsters might be a scary foe to fight
But I’ll take the stand
if I can stop your tears and wipe them dry
(I’ll make you feel magical!)
If my pain's a type of cure for peace, I don’t mind
I can play as a nurse healing you everyday
So what if I might shed a tear, get some bruises?
A wipe is all I need to clean the cherry blush away, Ha!
Fighting through the night, but I’m wide awake
It can all be so hard for me to get through the day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
Wrapped in a cute bandaid
I can take the pain
Fight all day
Fill up the syringe
With love heal up the world
And go again
(Uryaoi!! Uryaoi!! Oh, fighter!)
(Super powerful Miku-chan!)
(Uryaoi!! Uryaoi!! Oh, cyber!)
(Miku Miku Miku go!)
And now, it's time for the moment you've been waiting for!
1! 2! 3! Ready?!
Miku Miku beam!
Keep going!
(Eh-eh-eh-eh-eh)
On my own
Without anyone to know
How my job’s not all rainbows
But then I think about your smile
(Your words are so lyrical)
I’m a magically bright, invincible girl!
If you need me to heal, go on and call out my name
When you find yourself going down a spiral
I’ll bonk away what puts you down, a pink hammer melee! Yah!
Fighting through the night, but I’m wide awake
All alone, it’s so hard for me to get through the day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
So I stand and embrace
Not another break
Any pain
I take it all away
In a world love all find
And go again
M@GICAL☆CURE! LOVE SHOT!
[Title: M@GICAL☆CURE! LOVE SHOT!]
Don't matter the pain, I'll try to be brave
As long as you can stay happy, I'm okay
I'm not gonna bend, I can be a cure for fixing your heart
And I'll play as a nurse, healing you every day
Your smile is enough to heal all my aches
Wrapped in a cute band-aid
If you're feeling pain, call my name, I'll be by your side
Then I see you smile, bright and bright again
Urya-oi!! Urya-oi!! Oh, fighter!
Super powerful Miku-chan!
Urya-oi!! Urya-oi!! Oh, cyber!
Miku Miku Miku go!
わあ、眠いよ
Whoa, I'm sleepy.
夢だった？！
It was a dream?!
炎夏
[Title: Enka]
知った
I knew it
救いのない形だった
It was a form without salvation
僕の声は
My voice...
知った
I knew it
救いのない赤い血が
Unsalvageable red blood...
流れているんだ
...is flowing.
ただただ襲い来る 影ばかり見て
Just staring at the shadows that keep attacking
揶揄う言葉 立ち上がれない夜風
Teasing words, a night breeze that won't let me stand up
淡く光る場所へ 裸足で駆け出したら
When I ran barefoot towards the dimly lit place
ただ膝を抱えている 君がいたんだから
Because you were there, just holding your knees
ENCOUNT!
悲劇ぶった 天国へ
To a heaven pretending to be a tragedy
不甲斐ない 瞳 ぎゅっと
Worthless eyes, squeezed tight
あの日 みつめた 君のせいだ
It's because of you who I stared at that day
はやく はやく...
Hurry, hurry...
身を委ねて
Surrender yourself
淡い 淡い 水面の向こうへと
Towards the other side of the faint, faint water surface
視線
Gaze
知った
I knew it
救いのない熱を持った
I held a heat without salvation
僕の炎夏
My Enka
知った
I knew it
憂いのない貴方の瞳は
Your eyes, without sorrow...
酷く
Cruelly...
酷く 酷く...
Cruelly, cruelly...
逢瀬としてる その顔に
At that face that acts like a meeting
触れてみたかった
I wanted to try touching it
だから
So...
ENCOUNT!
喜劇ぶった
To a heaven pretending to be a comedy
天国へ
pretending to be a comedy
だから ENCOUNT!
So ENCOUNT!
悲劇ぶった天国へ
Into a tragic heaven
不甲斐ない瞳
With worthless eyes
きっと、あの日みつめた貴方のせいだ
It's surely the fault of you, who I stared at that day
はやく、はやく... はやく息をとめて
Hurry, hurry... Hurry and hold your breath
淡い淡い水面のむこうへと
Towards the beyond of the faint, faint water surface
白い光をみつめていると
When staring at the white light,
急な痛みに襲われる
A sudden pain attacks me.
僕は私を保っていられなくなること
That I will no longer be able to maintain myself...
それをこの小さな器(からだ)が証明している
This tiny vessel proves it.
はじめに、安堵するきみがみたい
First, I want to see you feel relieved.
つぎに、きたいしたい
Next, I want to hope.
この場所で戦いなど起こっていない。
There was no major battle here.
少なくともこの世界線では...
At least not in this timeline...
だが探偵には分かっていた。
But the detective knows...
彼女が見たものは決して夢ではないことを。
...what she saw was no dream.
心の中にはまだ殺戮の匂いが漂っている。
The smell of the carnage still lingers in her mind.
かつての彼女にまとわりついていた、あの匂い。
It's a scent that was, at one time, so familiar to her.
探偵としての生活も今では順調だが、
That stench would still linger on her...
そうでなければあの匂いからは離れることができなかったでしょう。
...if the detective's life didn't take a turn for the better.
今でも...あの頃の日々がリアルな夢のようにまとわりつく。
Even now... her days felt more like the real dream.
終わるべくして終わったおとぎ話。
A fairytale. Maybe one that deserved to end.
どこまで行っても彼女は、生まれ持った本質から逃れることはできない。
Because, at the end of the day, she can never run away from her nature.
それでも今は違う。今の彼女には仲間がいる。
But she's not just that anymore. She has friends to thank for that.
それが、別の世界線の彼女とは違う点なのかもしれない。
Maybe that was what separated her from the other version.
もしかしたらあの子は、幸せに生きることのできた世界線があったのだろうかと、
And, maybe... that version of herself just wanted a ray of hope,
そんな一筋の希望を求めていたのだろうか。
...to know that there was one timeline where things worked out.
そしてその幸せな世界線というのは、ここではないまた別の世界線のことかもしれない...
Or perhaps this was never about the detective...
考えが頭を巡るものの、答えが出ることはない。
So many thoughts run amok inside her head, but they're forever left unanswered.
何にせよ、探偵は自身の血塗られた過去を忘れることはないでしょう。
Whatever the case, the detective won't forget her bloody past,
しかしまた後戻りするつもりもない。
But she isn't going to revert to it either.
彼女はこれからも仲間とともに進む。
She will continue to move forward with her friends,
望んだ結末を迎えられなかった別の自分達のためにも。
And for all the variants who didn't get their desired ending.
探偵アーニャ・メルフィッサは、
The detective, Anya Melfissa,
明日に向かって生き続ける。
Will keep on living for her own tomorrow.
Anya Melfissa Birthday Live 2026!
How did everyone like it? Oh my goodness!
やっと今年も参りました、アーニャの誕生日です！
Finally, it's here again this year, Anya's birthday!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you all like it?
This time, I tried to incorporate a little bit of story into my 3D birthday celebration.
And I think it turned out pretty nice, you know?
You get story part and also live part,
and I think it turned out pretty well.
And also, how was my new original song? Oh my goodness!
How was my new original song? It was good, wasn't it? I hope you all liked it!
新曲もね、あの、歌わせていただきました。
I got to sing my new song too.
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you all like it?
Haa! Oh my god!
I celebrated... uh...
I celebrated my birthday with
a lot of friends too this year!
Yeah! A lot of the girls came
to celebrate my birthday...
...and also Detective Anya
managed to solve that mission!
Wow, she's got it! Detective Anya!
Did you guys like Detective Anya as well?
Detective Anya was pretty cool,
but not as cool as me!
Oh my god! And also...
special guests! There were special guests!
Oh my god, I can't believe I got to
sing with Hatsune Miku!
Hatsune Miku-chan!
Oh my god, she was really cute!
And also for the narration for my story part,
Ueda Reina-san narrated!
Oh my god! Ueda Reina-san also...
narrated the story part too!
上田麗奈さんもね、
Ueda Reina-san also...
ストーリーパートのナレーションもね、
...narrated the story part too.
上田麗奈さんがやってくれました！
Ueda Reina-san did it for me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ミクちゃんとも歌ったし、
I sang with Miku-chan too,
いや盛りだくさんでしたね、今年。
it was really packed this year.
Oh my god! Lots of wild things happening
on this year's birthday live!
How did you guys like it?
How did you guys like it? Oh my gosh!
Yeah! I had a lot of fun!
But... I would like to make
an announcement this year!
It's the usual.
ここで告知があります！
I have an announcement here!
I have an announcement to make!
Let me make an announcement!
はい！こちら！
Yes! This!
Oh my god! What is that? Who is that?
Is that me? Yes, it is!
We're releasing some new
merchandises too this year!
What do we have?
Let's take a look at them, shall we?
そして、えっと、一つずつ見ていきましょう。
And, let's look at them one by one.
まずはこちらです！
First is this!
Woo! It's a canvas art!
Study Time with Anya! The canvas art!
Oh my god, this illustration is so cute!
It's illustrated by Lunar-sensei!
Lunar先生にイラストを
Lunar-sensei drew
書いていただきました！かわいい！
the illustration! So cute!
The theme is, you know, literary girl!
Oh my god, so smart! So intelligent!
文系少女という
The theme is...
テーマになっております！
...a "literary girl"!
次はこちら！
Next is this!
Study Time with Anya! The notebook!
This is, I think this is my first notebook!
I've never had a notebook
as a merchandise before!
Oh my goodness! Please use this
lots for all your notes, for anything!
色々メモしてね、
Please take lots of notes,
オリジナルノートです！出ます！
it's an original notebook! It's coming out!
と、次はこちら！
And, next is this!
Oh! It's a pen case!
How cute is that? ペンポーチです！
How cute is that? It's a pen pouch!
ペンポーチも初かな？ノートも初らしいし、
Is the pen pouch also a first? The notebook is too,
ペンポーチもなんと、え、初です！
and the pen pouch is also a first!
ぜひ一緒にね、あのノートと使ってください！
Please use it together with that notebook!
Use this along with the notebook!
I think they would go
really well together, okay?
次は、こちら！
Next is this!
今年もボイスが出ます！
A voice pack is coming out this year too!
そして今年も、アーニャが
And this year too, Anya
台本を書かせていただいております！
wrote the script!
I wrote the script as usual,
as usual for every year!
I wrote the script for this situational voice,
so please get it! Please get it!
Oh yeah, the voice will be in Japanese
but there will be scripts in Bahasa Indonesia,
English, and Japanese.
ちなみにボイス自体は日本語になりますけど、
By the way, the voice itself is in Japanese,
台本もついてきます。
but scripts are included.
インドネシア語と英語と日本語の台本があります！
There are scripts in Indonesian, English, and Japanese!
ぜひ聴いてください！
Please listen to it!
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is this!
Oh my god! Limited edition has...
what is that? A hand-signed autograph?
Oh my god, it's the first for me!
Anya's first ever hand-signed
autograph for limited edition!
Please get them! なんと、今年はサイン入りです！
Please get them! This year it's signed!
今年はサイン入りです！なんと、なんと、なんと！
This year it's signed! Wow!
初、初ですね、アーニャが自らサインをして、
It's the first time Anya is signing it herself,
初なので、ぜひ皆さん、
so please everyone,
この機会でゲットしてください！
get it on this occasion!
Yeah, please get the limited edition!
And for the standard edition, it includes
a foil-stamped replica autograph,
so don't worry if you miss out
on the limited edition! Yeah!
ということでグッズ紹介は以上です！
That's all for the merch presentation!
That's all for the merch!
introduction
And another announcement is that...
my original song, the one that you guys heard...
...it's called ENCA or ENCOUNT by the way.
It will be releasing digitally...
It will be releasing digitally in like a few hours.
...at 12 AM your time zone on 13 March.
Yay! Yippee!
So in like... in like a few hours, yeah.
Yay!
なんとね、デジタルリリース。
And you know, there's a digital release.
新曲のデジタルリリースもあります。
There's also a digital release for my new song.
13日の0時です。
It's at midnight on the 13th.
よろしくお願いします。
Please check it out.
そしてこのあと、
And after this,
メンバーシップで配信もするのでぜひ見てください。
I'll be streaming for members, so please watch.
There will be a special encore for members only after this.
So members, Melhomies, let's go.
There will be a membership-only stream after this.
So please come and watch.
It will be in 3D by the way.
So you guys might want to check it out.
Yippee!
Okay, are you guys ready? Are you guys ready?
Well, this live is ending but we still have membership after this.
So I will see you guys there.
For members, I will see you guys there.
And for non-members, thank you so much for coming...
...and for watching my 3D birthday live.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Thank you, thank you.
And I wonder if you guys also posted a lot...
...using the hashtag.
I sure hope you guys did.
Yay! Thank you so much.
And... otsu-Kris! Bye-bye.
Otsu-Kris everyone!
The Great Ancient Detective's Bizarre Investigation+
[Title: The Great Ancient Detective's Bizarre Investigation+]